<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xheni</title>
    <description>InfoSec student, Nextcloud &amp; phpList contributor, Open Labs Hackerspace member, RGSoC alumna,  &amp; Inter fan</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 02:33:23 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 02:33:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning advanced PHP with phpList and Treehouse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The transition from being a student to the world of real work can be quite challenging. But if you are just starting out in the tech industry, combining online learning with contributing to Open Source allows you to develop your skills and gain experience in collaborative software development and management. I am a student and Open Source enthusiast who has contributed to several projects in recent years. During the last two months, I have combined online classrooms and workshops with an internship at phpList to develop my skills and practices. This has been my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enterprise-skills-with-online-learning&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise skills with online learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two months ago my most daunting question was which training platform to use to sharpen my PHP skills. It needed to fit my skill level and learning style. There is no single “best” course that fits everyone’s needs; we needed to find a platform which met the criteria. I was looking to extend my existing programming skills with newer and more sophisticated PHP systems and techniques. The courses needed to suit my &lt;strong&gt;intermediate level&lt;/strong&gt; and include coding exercises, as I like to learn ‘by doing’. While I found many PHP courses for beginners, intermediate and advanced courses were very difficult to find. &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/topic:php&quot;&gt;Team Treehouse&lt;/a&gt; was the only offering that convinced me because it covered more advanced topics such as &lt;strong&gt;Object Oriented&lt;/strong&gt; PHP and &lt;strong&gt;testing frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-treehouse-works&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Treehouse works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treehouse has a library which is a complete catalog of all the content that they offer. You can browse by &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/type:workshop&quot;&gt;type&lt;/a&gt;, topic or &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/library/sort:difficulty&quot;&gt;difficulty&lt;/a&gt;. Furthermore, there are different &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/tracks/objectoriented-php-2&quot;&gt;tracks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to choose from. Each track is a selection of courses with a common theme, like a certain programming language or a aspect of web development. The track acts as a roadmap so you know what to learn next, those are more of a guidance though and you are not forced to pick the courses in a specific order, allowing for a modular mix of topics. A course in Team Treehouse usually consists of &lt;strong&gt;video lectures&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;project code&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;code challenges&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;quizzes&lt;/strong&gt;. The combination of these methods of delivering content is a good means for ensuring that students will retain the knowledge of each course. I absolutely like the Treehouse’s approach to their videos. Most of them are are very short with good pacing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/treehouse1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;php coding demonstration&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PHP coding demonstration in a Treehouse video lecture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each individual lesson within a course has a video lecture, project code to experiment with, and a “&lt;strong&gt;workspace&lt;/strong&gt;” where you can make changes to the project code and see the results right away. If you have an active pro account, you can &lt;strong&gt;download course files&lt;/strong&gt; such as videos and video transcript for offline learning. Over the last two months, I completed 9 Treehouse courses in all, each chosen for their real-world usefulness and relevance to phpList &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phplist/phplist3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phpList/phplist4-core&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP Basics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Object-oriented PHP basics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extending object-oriented PHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP standards and best practices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP databases with PDO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP standards and best practices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP user authentication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating PHP with databases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended the following &lt;strong&gt;workshops&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dependency Management with Composer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic Error Handling with PHP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teachers-notes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teacher’s Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Teacher’s Notes for each video appear on the left-most tab below the video player. There you can find notes such as a summary of the lesson and useful links provided by the teacher. In my opinion, the links in the teacher’s notes worth the time to read because all knowledge that can improve your understanding is worth your time to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;quizzes-and-code-challenges&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quizzes and Code Challenges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/challenges.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A code challenge question on Treehouse&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A code challenge question on Treehouse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quizzes require a certain number of correct answers to pass. The only thing that I don’t like about them is that I’m not told why my answer is wrong, especially for the fill in the blank questions. The code challenges require writing some real code to test your knowledge and skill. There are two components involved in the Code Challenge. One component is the editor interface that you interact with and this is the only component you really see and touch. The other is the component that actually evaluates the code you write to see if it is correct. The code challenges and the quizzes help you to solidify your understanding. If you pay attention to the videos and write down concepts, it makes passing the code challenges and quizzes much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;workspaces&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workspaces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workspace is a fully browser-based code editor. You can use it to work alongside a Treehouse course. Each Workspace has a total storage limit of 50 MB. Currently, students are allowed to have up to 100 Workspaces created at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivational-tracking-tools&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivational tracking tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/badge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I earned +30 points for unlocking this badge&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I earned +30 points for unlocking this badge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Treehouse really knows how to motivate students to complete their courses. First of all, there are &lt;strong&gt;badges&lt;/strong&gt;. Everybody loves badges. Students get badges for reaching certain goals. There are always new badges being added to accompany new lessons and new courses. Another incentive tool is the &lt;strong&gt;motivational email&lt;/strong&gt; you get from the teacher when you complete the course. Next is the &lt;strong&gt;points system&lt;/strong&gt;. You get points in each area of Team Treehouse by completing courses and lessons. The more lessons you complete in, for example, PHP, the more points in the PHP area you get. Team Treehouse tracks both your points in each area and your total points. You also get points by posting on the Team Treehouse forum. Furthermore, it &lt;strong&gt;tracks your progress&lt;/strong&gt; in percentage system. You can see what percent of the total amount of content in a given track you have completed. This is a really good measure of your progress, and it feels great to see how far you have come. These incentive methods are very good for keeping the student focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;treehouse-community&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treehouse community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treehouse community is the best place to talk with your fellow students, asking questions, getting your questions answered, answering your fellow students’ questions and making it easier to make connections with like-minded folks going through the same journey as you are.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course quality varies from teacher to teacher and the PHP courses are taught by different teachers. Some teachers may be skilled in their profession, but don’t manage to communicate well with students. Also, some of them did not offer coding challenges, but only quizzes. Furthermore, not all teachers sent out motivational emails at the end of the course which would have made for a nicer learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-familiar-with-phplist&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting familiar with phpList&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t the first time I took an online course, but it’s the first time I’ve been really enjoying it. But during the training time I felt like the coding exercises were not enough for me, so I asked my phpList mentor to assign me some real-world bugs to fix. The phpList source code was easy to find on on GitHub and I registered an account for myself on the project’s Mantis bug tracker. I started off with issues tagged as ‘quick-fix’ – these ones were well described and easy to fix. Soon I was working on the source code and submitting my first pull requests. This way I put my Treehouse knowledge to immediate use and my motivation got quite a boost once I saw my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phpList/phplist3/pulls?q=is%3Apr+author%3Axh3n1+is%3Aclosed&quot;&gt;PRs&lt;/a&gt; being merged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer: This article was originally published on phpList blog.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 11:04:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/Learning-advanced-php-with-phplist-and-treehouse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/Learning-advanced-php-with-phplist-and-treehouse/</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>course</category>
        
        <category>phplist</category>
        
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>phplist</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>34c3, Endlich, normale Leute...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chaos Communication Congress is an annual conference organized by the Chaos Computer Club. The congress features a variety of lectures and workshops on technical and political issues related to Security, Cryptography, Privacy and online Freedom of Speech. The event takes place regularly at the end of the year since 1984, with the current date and duration (December 27–30) established in 2005. It is considered one of the largest events of this kind, alongside the DEF CON in Las Vegas.
&lt;em&gt;This is what I read on Wikipedia before I decided to go there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaos Communication Congress has been running for 34 years, and this was the first year that Congress was hosted in Leipzig.
Around 15,000 people took part in this remarkable event. No doubt, it’s the biggest hacker conference in Europe.
Apart from the official conference program, the CCC also offers space for assemblies, lightning talks, developer meetings, art installations, workshops, and special places for kids to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tuwat!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/logo-tuwat.png&quot; alt=&quot;tuwat&quot; title=&quot;tuwat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s motto, “tuwat!”, which is a slang-dialect for “do something!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first Congress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A security professional told me how cool this conference is and convinced me to go there. But I went there with Jona, my RGSoC teammate. We arrived in Berlin one night before the CCC, and we almost missed our flixbus to Leipzig, because I wanted to see the Brandenburger Tor. What a night !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CCC is more than a ‘hacker’ conference. It’s a community get-together and the community consists of all creatures of the web who share the common vision for an open and free technological society: hackers, programmers,hactivists, artists, philosophers, engineers, trollers, robots, aliens etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/leipzig.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pool&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been in other Congress Centers, but The Congress Center Leipzig (CCL) was huge and stunning.
 There was one huge hall (Hall 2), which was filled with all the assemblies and two halls filled with the big lecture halls.
The coolest hall to hang out was the one with the  Assemblies where hackerspaces and interest groups get together and bring their computers and coolest toys, doing what they do best —hacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/rockets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rocket&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also this “pool area” which was very outstanding and they played very good music. Nerds know how to party ;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-pool.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;pool&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big glass hall allowed daylight consumption and made it obvious when that was missing.
 I was very amazed, especially at night, by all those neon lights, art decorations, nerdy atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-rocket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rocket&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I obviously saw some talks about security, and even about open source satellites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-talk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;talk&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited assemblies, played some games, listened to robotic music, met some old friends and of course grabbed a lot of stickers. Totally enjoyable experience!
I spend most of the time at Nextcloud assembly, together with other Nextclouders.
  By the way, on the third day, I was wearing the Nextcloud T-shirt and guess what? People came to me and asked about Nextcloud or just said: “I love Nextcloud, awesome software”.
   The real soul of the Congress is people getting together, making something crazy and temporary, learning new things, and simply having fun.
  I have seen strange things.
  What really got my attention was an impressive 3D zoetrope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-robot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;robot&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;
   Also the pneumatic robot-dog-horse-with-gasmask, which is driven by an Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-face.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;face&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;
   This one scared me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make Mate, not War&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know that Mate is geeks’ favourite drink?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/floramate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mate&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back in the “Real World”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have been to a Chaos Communication Congress, I know that feeling, the strange realization after it’s all over and that you’re back in the “real world”. It’s somehow alienating in comparison to being surrounded by computer geeks, artists, hackers, coders and other like-minded individuals over the four days of the Congress. There was this hand-written poster “Endlich, normale Leute” — “At last, normal people” — which is irony piled on irony but the sentiment is still right for certain strange values of “normal”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random photos taken with my Samsung Galaxy Note 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/alien.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alien&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-ihavenoidea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ihavenoidea&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-unix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;unix&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-more.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;more&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-chaos.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;chaos&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/events/34c3-chaos2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;chaos&quot; title=&quot;34c3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 16:04:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/34c3-chaos-communication-congress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/34c3-chaos-communication-congress/</guid>
        
        <category>Congress</category>
        
        <category>hackers</category>
        
        
        <category>Event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> Git Workshop at Open Labs </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Git is a free and open source distributed version control system designed to handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency. It is the most popular VCS used by thousand developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the  Rails Girls Summer of Code,  I barely had any experience with Git and I knew only some concepts. 
Thanks to the Git documentation and the very friendly community over at Nextcloud, I learned many new Git commands.:).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a member at Open Labs Hackerspace and I have noticed that many members of our community are interested in learning Git. Thus, I decided to organize a workshop about Git. Why not? Knowledge sharing is very important to me  and it is the main reason why I advocate Open Source. It’s not tham I am a Git expert, not at all, but still I think that If know something that others don’t, share it with them.
I talked with Sidorela, another open source enthusiast member of Open Labs about it and together we decided to host the first Git workshop at Open Labs. We proposed the idea of organizing a workshop at Open Labs Forum and as I expected they were interested in learning some commands.
The workshop went very good. We talked a bit about Git history and Git design in general and then we explained some concepts to them. We practiced and run the most useful git commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mergeconflict.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;merge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A link of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xh3n1/Personal/blob/master/presentation/introductiontoGit.pdf&quot;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; can be found on my Personal GitHub repo. 
The feedback that they gave us after the event was really good, and it encourages me to continue with Git workshops and not only.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 11:04:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/Git-Workshop-At-OpenLabs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/Git-Workshop-At-OpenLabs/</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>openlabs</category>
        
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eps3.3_m3tadata.par2, a security review  </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Metadata. The story behind the data. Getting information is one thing, but how it was created, where, by whom, can often be illuminating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/metadata2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Elliot&quot; title=&quot;Elliot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elliot with plenty of metadata&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What caught my attention this time was one of the Elliot’s monologues about metadata and our privacy online.
Our friend mentioned that metadata from pictures which are  posted on social media by us , for example on  Facebook and Instagram can reveal a lot  more about the ones who took the pictures and they don’t know it. Information like who took the photo and the location, GPS coordinates. This is how he found the  address of the person who hacked his computer and this is how FBI found the person behind the fsociety video posted on VIMEO . Elliot’s thoughts about social media and metadata is not a big surprise for people who are concerned about their privacy online. 
One week before I watched this episode, believe it or not, I was reading about EXIF metadata.&lt;br /&gt;
It was quite interesting that Elliot mentionied specifically EXIF data when he was telling us  about metadata and we know that our friend is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/metadata.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Elliot&quot; title=&quot;Elliot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if facebook, instagram or twitter wipes the metadata when actually posting a picture online, it will still get the raw photo when you uploaded it. An advice would be to use  a Metadata Anonamization Toolkit if you really don’t want your pictures  to have metadata when you upload them online,  to lock down social media accounts to maximum privacy levels, disable location-based posting, and remember that what you post online is out there forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-confuse-the-bugs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to confuse the bugs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When  Elliot was confronting Darlene, he  puts a device that created a  noise to confuse the bugs. This device it is known as a audio jammer and it was designed to obscure human speech from listening devices. These devices do exist in reality and you  can even find  mobile apps  which turn your smartphone into an audio jammer. These devices are legal to use, so consider using them if you are paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 11:04:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/Mr-Robot-Season-3-Episode-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/Mr-Robot-Season-3-Episode-4/</guid>
        
        <category>movies</category>
        
        <category>Mr Robot</category>
        
        
        <category>movies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eps3.2_1egacy.so, a flashback episode </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first recap of Mr Robot episodes. It’s full of spoilers and if you haven’t watched it yet,  DO NO READ IT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all I loved the Shining style opening credits. The “Eps3.2_1egacy.so” is a flashback episode dedicated to one character: Tyrell Wellick.  It  answers to many questions like : What happened to Tyrell the night of the 5/9 hack, Why didn’t he contact his wife ? What’s his role in the Dark Army and on the Stage 2? How is he connected to Elliot?  The weird relationship between Elliot and Tyrell is the focus of this episode. 
The flashback begins on the night of the hack as Elliot has just put his plan in motion. While Tyrell is staring at his partner computer, Elliot walks over to the popcorn machine, and we know that the gun is in there. We first assumed that he killed Tyrell but he  aims the gun at Tyrell, pulls the trigger and no shot is fired.  Tyrell is not scared. He laughs and sees this as divine intervention. Mr Robot gave the gun to Tyrell and told him if Elliot ever wants to stop the stage 2, he should shoot him. 
Irving and the Dark Army shows up with questions for Tyrell. Mr. Robot has no clue who he is and he is confused.
We’ve gone back in time to see what Tyrell was up to while Elliot spent time in jail. Tyrell undergoes some disturbing questioning at the cabin. We know now that he has some daddy issues and  declares his loyalty to Elliot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tyrell2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tyrell&quot; title=&quot;Tyrell&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tyrell grows his beard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He spends some months in the woods, alone and grows his beard. He chops wood, continually checks up on the news about Joanna  , and even has access to a baby cam that allows him to watch his child sleep… The news that Joanna has a new man on her side make him feel nervous. He goes outside. He is  spotted by a cop and he is captured by him. The cop plans to transfer him to FBI , but Agent Santiago kills him and takes  Tyrell back to the cabin. It confirms that Santiago was working all this time for the Dark Army as we all  suspected.
When Tyrell and Elliot finally meet back up at the Cab, Elliot has absolutely no idea why is he there. They went to the warehouse and we know the end. Tyrell is feeling guilty for shooting him. He is panicked  while Elliot is operated on in the warehouse. On the other side Angela, looks so calm and cold.  Tyrell is more emotional about Elliot getting shot than Angela. She tells Tyrell that sometimes Elliot is another person. Nothing is ever as it seems. Tyrell’s world is shaken and his perception suddenly changed. Ideas of perception dominate the episode.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 21:04:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/Mr-Robot-Season-3-Episode-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/Mr-Robot-Season-3-Episode-3/</guid>
        
        <category>movies</category>
        
        <category>Mr Robot</category>
        
        
        <category>movies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LibOCon and libre Ladies...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;LibOCon is the annual gathering of the LibreOffice community. At LibOCon, LibreOffice users gather to network and meet key LibreOffice developers, designers, localizers, documenters, supporters and marketers, and to learn about the latest in LibreOffice development.
I have been a LibreOffice user for many years and this year I joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://conference.libreoffice.org/&quot;&gt;LibreOffice Conference&lt;/a&gt; from 11-13 October in Rome, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/icontributed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Suela and Xheni during their presentation. Credits: Redon Skikuli CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibOCon 2017 was hosted inside historical buildings, the property of the City of Rome. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Suela_Palushi&quot;&gt;Suela&lt;/a&gt; and I talked  about “How to retain new contributors?”,
“Our experience as newcomers” and “Contributions to open source” - survey. Here are some of the results of the survey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon2.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon6.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon5.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon7.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some interesting answers when  we asked them “How do community activities affect your experience as a contributor?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It makes me feel that I am doing the things right. Each time I generate a contribution, I feel
happiness because I am spending time of my life for the benefit of projects that will useful for other people around the world while I sharing this experience with other human beings”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Gain experience and new friends ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In 1:1/groups brainstorming is much faster and enjoyable”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Get to know more people in the same field of interests as mine”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Community gives you outside connections, adds purpose and enjoyment to the work we’re all doing”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During LibOCon and HackFest I had the opportunity to meet other open source ladies who contribute to LibreOffice and we took this picture &amp;lt;3. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/librecon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;LibreLadies CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great time in Rome. Beautiful city and good friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ps: The next LibOCon will be held in Tirana. See you there!
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/romanforum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Roman Forum CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 17:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/liboconandlibreladies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/liboconandlibreladies/</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>girlsintech</category>
        
        <category>conference</category>
        
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CryptoParty in Tirana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy is the space in which ideas are developed, to retreat into whenever you want. This space is not only physical but digital as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a CryptoParty?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CryptoParties are free and open for everyone, but especially ​those without prior knowledge, who haven’t yet attended one.
CryptoParty is a decentralized movement with constantly happening activities in the entire world. The goal of this movement is sharing as much knowledge to as many individuals as possible on how to protect ourselves in the digital world. This worldwide effort introduces the basis of cryptography both in theory and practice, such as encrypted communication, prevention of espionage when navigating on the internet, anonymity on Tor netwyork, cryptography with public key, storage encryption, Virtual Private Networks (VPN) etc. The project consists of a series of workshops free and open for everyone .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first CryptoParty in Albania&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To join this worldwide effort and to inform about the dangers of the digital world, the importance of online privacy and exchange of practical knowledge to protect our privacy, Open Labs with the support of Arjen Kamphuis and Ardian Haxha have organized CryptoParty Tirana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cryptoparty1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CryptoParty&quot; title=&quot;Cryptoparty&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;CryptoParty Albania. Credits: CC-BY-4.0 Andis Rado&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CryptoParty  took place at Innovation Hub Tirana  and  gathered  many technology enthusiasts , developers, students, academics, journalists  and people who are concerned about privacy and information security.
It was the first CryptoParty in Albania and  it  was really well-organized, with multiple talks and  workshops like:  private browsing, file-encryption, email-encryption, debian installation etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cryptoparty2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CryptoParty&quot; title=&quot;Cryptoparty&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Data encryption workshop. Credits: CC-BY-4.0 Andis Rado&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there were people who come down on the side of the government: “I have nothing to hide”…
The nothing to hide argument states that government surveillance programs do not threaten privacy unless they uncover illegal activities, and that if they do uncover illegal activities, the person committing these activities does not have the right to keep them private. Hence, a person who favors this argument may state “I’ve got nothing to hide” and therefore does not express opposition to government surveillance.An individual using this argument may say that a person should not have worries about government or surveillance if he/she has “nothing to hide.”-Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Arguing that you don’t care about the right to privacy because you have nothing to hide, is no different than saying you don’t care about free speech because you have nothing to say.” – E. Snowden.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emilio Mordini, philosopher and psychoanalyst, argued that the “nothing to hide” argument is inherently paradoxical. People do not need to have “something to hide” in order to hide “something”. What is relevant is not what is hidden, rather the experience that there is an intimate area, which could be hidden, whose access could be restricted. Psychologically speaking, we become individuals through the discovery that we could hide something to others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 17:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/CryptoParty-in-Tirana/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/CryptoParty-in-Tirana/</guid>
        
        <category>cryptoparty</category>
        
        
        <category>crypto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails Girls Summer of Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time seems to fly by so fast when you are a student of Rails Girls Summer of Code and a contributor of a project you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-they-started-to-get-into-the-open-source-world&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How they started to get into the open source world!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jona.azizaj.com&quot;&gt;Jona&lt;/a&gt; and Xheni met each other 5 years ago at the University of Tirana, Faculty of Economy because both of them wanted to study for Business Informatics. At the beginning they didn’t “like” each other a lot because Xheni was an Inter fan while Jona a Milan fan, different teams that play in Italy and their fans “fight” a lot with each other. YES, you read it very well, so don’t get surprised if they know football rules/ football players/ teams pretty well because they are crazy about football. The good news is that they found something in common, yaaay! They attended together the first edition of OSCAL, &lt;a href=&quot;https://oscal.openlabs.cc/&quot;&gt;Open Source Conference Albania&lt;/a&gt;, the first conference in Albania dedicated only to open source software. After meeting a lot of other FLOSS enthusiasts at the conference, they discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://openlabs.cc/en/&quot;&gt;Open Labs&lt;/a&gt; that is the community behind OSCAL. Open Labs organizes a lot of events dedicated to different open source projects like GNU/Linux, Mozilla, Wikipedia, OpenStreetMap, LibreOffice etc. Both of them were intrigued by the world of Linux, that’s how they first started contributing to open source and became FLOSS advocates. Now that they have been part of Open Labs for four years, you see them part of different open source communities because being part of a community has helped them a lot to gain new experiences, learn new things, make new friends and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rgsoc-lets-apply&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RGSoC, let’s apply!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jona’s and Xheni’s latest involvement into open source is &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;, a suite of client-server software for creating and using file hosting service, where their contributions consisted mostly on promoting Nextcloud and translating it in their local language (shqip).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At OSCAL (third edition) they met Jan-Christoph Borchardt and had the chance to talk with him. After some months, they saw his tweet about a
dedicated scholarship program that aims to foster diversity in Open Source since 2013, called “Rails Girls Summer of Code”. Both of them were
really enthusiast and happy to hear about such a great opportunity that could help girls develop their skills and gain new exciting experiences. After posting this on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.openlabs.cc/&quot;&gt;Open Labs forum&lt;/a&gt; to share it with all the girls, they even organized an “unofficial” meeting with all the interested girls to help each other with the process. It was the first time that 4 teams from Albania applied to be part of RGSoC!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-nextcloud&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Nextcloud?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After picking each other as teammates, Jona and Xheni had to decide about the project they wanted to spend all their summer working on. Wait, what about the name of the team?
Hmmm let’s say they needed only a couple of hours to find the appropriate name for them. And it was not very difficult, because both of them are &lt;strong&gt;CODEAHOLICS&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, I mean it! They stay awake all night long and they like to sleep in the morning because for them is way easier to work when the place is very quiet, people are sleeping and the only thing that they can hear is their favorite music. Okay now let’s get back to the topic. After scouting all the projects listed, the first one that was deemed a perfect fit for them was Nextcloud. Why? Because they were already using it and they were familiar (not a lot) with the community. Both of them believe that when you use something and you like it, it’s very easy for you to start promoting and working on it, in this way you will always do something that you love and are not forced to. They decided to work on the contacts app and documentation part during the summer.
After finishing the application all the albanian teams were “stressed” waiting about the final result. Who could imagine that we would be one of the lucky teams, being the first albanian team part of RGSoC! Imagine their happy faces when they saw the approval email, &lt;strong&gt;yaaay&lt;/strong&gt; :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Codeaholics Logo. (Photo: Anxhelo Lushka, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the challenges that our team has faced during this period:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First of all, installing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt; server locally was not as easy for us as we first assumed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before attending RGSoC we barely had any experience with Git on an important open source project as Nextcloud with a lot of people contributing into it. During our journey we made many mistakes and had to do some researches on different Git commands. Thanks to the friendly community over at Nextcloud, we learned many new Git commands, now it’s just a matter of remembering them :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We fought a lot with JavaScript and in particular AngularJS. We wanted to work on something new for us and that’s why we chose the Contacts App. We were complete beginners on AngularJS and during the first weeks we were mainly focused on reading and watching tutorials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another challenging thing was working remotely together over different time-zones (6 hours difference) as Jona was attending “Flock to Fedora Conference” in Boston.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_angularJS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Too much AngularJS, not enough coffee. (Photo: Jona &amp;amp; Xheni, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;things-we-have-learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things we have learned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the challenges we had during our summer, we have learned a lot of new things. Here are some of the things we can recall:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pair programming, a very good way to keep each other on task. Brainstorming helps a lot when you work as a team. Don’t forget that two brains are better than one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AngularJS concepts: we learned about controllers, services, promises, filters and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript is the world’s most misunderstood programming language but we understand it better now :).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We learned about vCard format specification.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Git Commands that were really useful for our daily job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asking for help because the communication is the key to solve some of the issues! There are always people out there willing to help, especially on the Nextcloud IRC channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_pairprogramming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pair Programming at Open Labs Hackerspace. (Photo: Jona &amp;amp; Xheni, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nextcloud-contributions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nextcloud contributions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an albanian idiom “-Fillimi i mbarë, gjysma e punës” (English equivalent: Well begun, is half done), therefore we created our first PR on our first week and we began contributing on Nextcloud by fixing some starter issues, opening new issues, testing and reviewing etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays we are mainly focused on developing a new feature: “favorite contacts”, allowing users to quickly favourite some of their contacts.  We are confident to have this feature finished by the end of the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will be next? We certainly will continue contributing on other Nextcloud apps, even after the summer ends because we really love the vibe that this community has and the friendly environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;girl-power-at-the-nextcloud-conference&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Girl Power at the Nextcloud conference!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about working on the open source projects are the conferences. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/codeaholics_AL&quot;&gt;Codeaholics&lt;/a&gt; joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/conf/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud Conference&lt;/a&gt; on 22-29 August in Berlin, Germany. We were the early birds who arrived in the morning on the first day, waiting for other contributors to join the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_nextcloud_conference.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Team Codeaholics at Nextcloud Conference. (Photo: Christoph Wurst, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we had the chance to meet our coaches Morris and Joas in person, our mentor joined us as well. We had four amazing days full of hacking and working on specific tasks on Nextcloud. It’s very helpful when you have your coaches nearby so you can directly ask them and clarify in case of any doubts. In addition to meeting our coaches we also met many other contributors during our stay in Berlin. Fun fact: We knew most of them already by their GitHub usernames, that’s why the first question we asked them was their github username. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We attended some talks related to the collaboration between Red Hat and Nextcloud, Collabora Online, how the Technical University of Berlin uses Nextcloud, Scalability Recommendations, Security etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the weekend, there were some lightning talks and workshops where we also shared &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OpMtsE_MICs&quot;&gt;our experience&lt;/a&gt; as RGSoC students with them (a lot of applauses in the end, yaaay)! It was a wonderful conference and a great opportunity to network with the community behind Nextcloud, which makes you feel more motivated to keep contributing.
And just for the record, coding while drinking Club Mate is one of the best feelings ever. (Try it :P)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_nextcloud.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nextcloud Conference. (Photo:Raghu Nayyar, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our stay in Berlin we attended the “Open Source Ladies” event together with Jan, which is an event that aims to help women contribute to open source projects and guide them how to join their communities. It was very nice to meet some new enthusiastic Open Source Ladies from Berlin and share our experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-will-we-miss-most&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will we miss most&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that RGSoC ended, we will miss a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our weekly meeting calls with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benediktdeicke&quot;&gt;supervisor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jancborchardt&quot;&gt;mentor&lt;/a&gt;  and coaches. It has been a pleasure working with all of them. By the way: Even though all of them were German and we have heard stories that Germans are very strict or that is very difficult to work with them we are very happy to admit that it is NOT true! Each wednesday that we have our weekly call, we were very happy to talk with them and hear their feedback because it was really helpful for us, that’s why this is one of the things we will miss most! (Thank you guys :D)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Status updates, because they helped us keep track of what we achieved and to set goals for our team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being able to focus full-time on open-source development and community building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-in-all&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All in All…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a never-to-be-forgotten summer - one of those summers that leave a rich heritage of beautiful memories in their going. Is it the end? Definitely NO, our journey does not end here. We are both open source enthusiasts and the gained experience we had this summer has inspired us even more to continue contributing to coding part of open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks RGSoC for this amazing experience we had during this summer, we are happy to be one of the RGSoC alumni now and share our journey with other people!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 17:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/Rails-Girls-Summer-Of-Code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/Rails-Girls-Summer-Of-Code/</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>girlsintech</category>
        
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C-base Hackerspace</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The c-base is the crashed spacestation in the center of Berlin. Nerds, Geeks, SciFi-Fans and digital activists founded the society in 1995. Since that time they reconstruct the space station and use it to share knowledge, interact with other species and provide a space for likeminded groups and individuals. Some people say, that the c-base is “the mother of all hackerspaces”, okay, maybe we will believe that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited C-base together with some friends from Open Labs Hackerspace ( The brightest hackerspace). It was one of the best things I did during my stay in Berlin this summer. Hopefully, I will visit it again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cbase.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cbase&quot; title=&quot;C-base &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In case of revolution, break glass! CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 17:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/c-base-hackerspace/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/c-base-hackerspace/</guid>
        
        <category>Places</category>
        
        <category>Hackerspace</category>
        
        
        <category>places</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oscal 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OSCAL (Open Source Conference Albania) is the first annual conference in Albania organized to promote software freedom, open source software, free culture and open knowledge, a global movement that originally started more than 25 years ago.
I have attended Oscal conferences since the beginning, except  last year and I am very glad that I didn’t miss  Oscal 2017.
The Conference took place at 13 &amp;amp; 14 May 2017 in Tirana and  gathered free libre open source technology users, developers, academics, governmental agencies and people who share the idea that software should be free and open ; that knowledge is a communal property and free and open to everyone.
Oscal’s mission is to educate Albanian youth, and not only, on Free and Open Source Software, its ideology and the great community behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/oscal2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oscal 2017&quot; title=&quot;Oscal Group Photo &quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Oscal 2017. Credits : Andis Rado.CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference is supported and organized by Open Labs , the community that promotes free libre open source culture in Albania since 2012.
The conference itself was well-organized, with multiple tracks of talks, workshops and of course infobooths.I attended some interesting talks and workshops and met new people and old friends, folks of open source, geeks and nerds.
I wanted to mention something else thing that makes OSCAL special and it the fact that male/female ratio seems to be the inverse of what you usually see in these kind of conferences. There are girls everywhere: infobooths, speakers and visitors. GREAT, huh?
There were also some cool and funny  posters ( albanian idioms and opensource jokes). I LOVED THEM!
Can’t wait for the next Oscal!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 17:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/Oscal-2017/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/Oscal-2017/</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>conference</category>
        
        <category>albania</category>
        
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
