<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xheni</title>
    <description>InfoSec student, Nextcloud contributor, Open Labs Hackerspace member, RGSoC alumna &amp; Inter fan</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 20:56:04 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 20:56:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>LibOCon and libre Ladies...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;LibOCon is the annual gathering of the LibreOffice community. At LibOCon, LibreOffice users gather to network and meet key LibreOffice developers, designers, localizers, documenters, supporters and marketers, and to learn about the latest in LibreOffice development.
I have been a LibreOffice user for many years and this year I joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://conference.libreoffice.org/&quot;&gt;LibreOffice Conference&lt;/a&gt; from 11-13 October in Rome, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/icontributed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Suela and Xheni during their presentation. Credits: Redon Skikuli CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibOCon 2017 was hosted inside historical buildings, the property of the City of Rome. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Suela_Palushi&quot;&gt;Suela&lt;/a&gt; and I talked  about “How to retain new contributors?”,
“Our experience as newcomers” and “Contributions to open source” - survey. Here are some of the results of the survey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon2.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon6.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon5.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/libocon7.png&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some interesting answers when  we asked them “How do community activities affect your experience as a contributor?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It makes me feel that I am doing the things right. Each time I generate a contribution, I feel
happiness because I am spending time of my life for the benefit of projects that will useful for other people around the world while I sharing this experience with other human beings”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Gain experience and new friends ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In 1:1/groups brainstorming is much faster and enjoyable”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Get to know more people in the same field of interests as mine”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Community gives you outside connections, adds purpose and enjoyment to the work we’re all doing”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During LibOCon and HackFest I had the opportunity to meet other open source ladies who contribute to LibreOffice and we took this picture &amp;lt;3. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/librecon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;LibreLadies CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great time in Rome. Beautiful city and good friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ps: The next LibOCon will be held in Tirana. See you there!
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/romanforum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;liboCon&quot; title=&quot;LibOCOn CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Roman Forum CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 17:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/liboconandlibreladies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/liboconandlibreladies/</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>girlsintech</category>
        
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails Girls Summer of Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time seems to fly by so fast when you are a student of Rails Girls Summer of Code and a contributor of a project you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-they-started-to-get-into-the-open-source-world&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How they started to get into the open source world!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jona.azizaj.com&quot;&gt;Jona&lt;/a&gt; and Xheni met each other 5 years ago at the University of Tirana, Faculty of Economy because both of them wanted to study for Business Informatics. At the beginning they didn’t “like” each other a lot because Xheni was an Inter fan while Jona a Milan fan, different teams that play in Italy and their fans “fight” a lot with each other. YES, you read it very well, so don’t get surprised if they know football rules/ football players/ teams pretty well because they are crazy about football. The good news is that they found something in common, yaaay! They attended together the first edition of OSCAL, &lt;a href=&quot;https://oscal.openlabs.cc/&quot;&gt;Open Source Conference Albania&lt;/a&gt;, the first conference in Albania dedicated only to open source software. After meeting a lot of other FLOSS enthusiasts at the conference, they discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://openlabs.cc/en/&quot;&gt;Open Labs&lt;/a&gt; that is the community behind OSCAL. Open Labs organizes a lot of events dedicated to different open source projects like GNU/Linux, Mozilla, Wikipedia, OpenStreetMap, LibreOffice etc. Both of them were intrigued by the world of Linux, that’s how they first started contributing to open source and became FLOSS advocates. Now that they have been part of Open Labs for four years, you see them part of different open source communities because being part of a community has helped them a lot to gain new experiences, learn new things, make new friends and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rgsoc-lets-apply&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RGSoC, let’s apply!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jona’s and Xheni’s latest involvement into open source is &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;, a suite of client-server software for creating and using file hosting service, where their contributions consisted mostly on promoting Nextcloud and translating it in their local language (shqip).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At OSCAL (third edition) they met Jan-Christoph Borchardt and had the chance to talk with him. After some months, they saw his tweet about a
dedicated scholarship program that aims to foster diversity in Open Source since 2013, called “Rails Girls Summer of Code”. Both of them were
really enthusiast and happy to hear about such a great opportunity that could help girls develop their skills and gain new exciting experiences. After posting this on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.openlabs.cc/&quot;&gt;Open Labs forum&lt;/a&gt; to share it with all the girls, they even organized an “unofficial” meeting with all the interested girls to help each other with the process. It was the first time that 4 teams from Albania applied to be part of RGSoC!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-nextcloud&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Nextcloud?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After picking each other as teammates, Jona and Xheni had to decide about the project they wanted to spend all their summer working on. Wait, what about the name of the team?
Hmmm let’s say they needed only a couple of hours to find the appropriate name for them. And it was not very difficult, because both of them are &lt;strong&gt;CODEAHOLICS&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, I mean it! They stay awake all night long and they like to sleep in the morning because for them is way easier to work when the place is very quiet, people are sleeping and the only thing that they can hear is their favorite music. Okay now let’s get back to the topic. After scouting all the projects listed, the first one that was deemed a perfect fit for them was Nextcloud. Why? Because they were already using it and they were familiar (not a lot) with the community. Both of them believe that when you use something and you like it, it’s very easy for you to start promoting and working on it, in this way you will always do something that you love and are not forced to. They decided to work on the contacts app and documentation part during the summer.
After finishing the application all the albanian teams were “stressed” waiting about the final result. Who could imagine that we would be one of the lucky teams, being the first albanian team part of RGSoC! Imagine their happy faces when they saw the approval email, &lt;strong&gt;yaaay&lt;/strong&gt; :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Codeaholics Logo. (Photo: Anxhelo Lushka, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the challenges that our team has faced during this period:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First of all, installing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt; server locally was not as easy for us as we first assumed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before attending RGSoC we barely had any experience with Git on an important open source project as Nextcloud with a lot of people contributing into it. During our journey we made many mistakes and had to do some researches on different Git commands. Thanks to the friendly community over at Nextcloud, we learned many new Git commands, now it’s just a matter of remembering them :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We fought a lot with JavaScript and in particular AngularJS. We wanted to work on something new for us and that’s why we chose the Contacts App. We were complete beginners on AngularJS and during the first weeks we were mainly focused on reading and watching tutorials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another challenging thing was working remotely together over different time-zones (6 hours difference) as Jona was attending “Flock to Fedora Conference” in Boston.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_angularJS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Too much AngularJS, not enough coffee. (Photo: Jona &amp;amp; Xheni, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;things-we-have-learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things we have learned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the challenges we had during our summer, we have learned a lot of new things. Here are some of the things we can recall:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pair programming, a very good way to keep each other on task. Brainstorming helps a lot when you work as a team. Don’t forget that two brains are better than one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AngularJS concepts: we learned about controllers, services, promises, filters and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript is the world’s most misunderstood programming language but we understand it better now :).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We learned about vCard format specification.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Git Commands that were really useful for our daily job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asking for help because the communication is the key to solve some of the issues! There are always people out there willing to help, especially on the Nextcloud IRC channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_pairprogramming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pair Programming at Open Labs Hackerspace. (Photo: Jona &amp;amp; Xheni, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nextcloud-contributions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nextcloud contributions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an albanian idiom “-Fillimi i mbarë, gjysma e punës” (English equivalent: Well begun, is half done), therefore we created our first PR on our first week and we began contributing on Nextcloud by fixing some starter issues, opening new issues, testing and reviewing etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays we are mainly focused on developing a new feature: “favorite contacts”, allowing users to quickly favourite some of their contacts.  We are confident to have this feature finished by the end of the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will be next? We certainly will continue contributing on other Nextcloud apps, even after the summer ends because we really love the vibe that this community has and the friendly environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;girl-power-at-the-nextcloud-conference&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Girl Power at the Nextcloud conference!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about working on the open source projects are the conferences. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/codeaholics_AL&quot;&gt;Codeaholics&lt;/a&gt; joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/conf/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud Conference&lt;/a&gt; on 22-29 August in Berlin, Germany. We were the early birds who arrived in the morning on the first day, waiting for other contributors to join the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_nextcloud_conference.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Team Codeaholics at Nextcloud Conference. (Photo: Christoph Wurst, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we had the chance to meet our coaches Morris and Joas in person, our mentor joined us as well. We had four amazing days full of hacking and working on specific tasks on Nextcloud. It’s very helpful when you have your coaches nearby so you can directly ask them and clarify in case of any doubts. In addition to meeting our coaches we also met many other contributors during our stay in Berlin. Fun fact: We knew most of them already by their GitHub usernames, that’s why the first question we asked them was their github username. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We attended some talks related to the collaboration between Red Hat and Nextcloud, Collabora Online, how the Technical University of Berlin uses Nextcloud, Scalability Recommendations, Security etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the weekend, there were some lightning talks and workshops where we also shared &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OpMtsE_MICs&quot;&gt;our experience&lt;/a&gt; as RGSoC students with them (a lot of applauses in the end, yaaay)! It was a wonderful conference and a great opportunity to network with the community behind Nextcloud, which makes you feel more motivated to keep contributing.
And just for the record, coding while drinking Club Mate is one of the best feelings ever. (Try it :P)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/codeaholics_nextcloud.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nextcloud Conference. (Photo:Raghu Nayyar, Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0 International.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our stay in Berlin we attended the “Open Source Ladies” event together with Jan, which is an event that aims to help women contribute to open source projects and guide them how to join their communities. It was very nice to meet some new enthusiastic Open Source Ladies from Berlin and share our experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-will-we-miss-most&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will we miss most&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that RGSoC ended, we will miss a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our weekly meeting calls with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benediktdeicke&quot;&gt;supervisor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jancborchardt&quot;&gt;mentor&lt;/a&gt;  and coaches. It has been a pleasure working with all of them. By the way: Even though all of them were German and we have heard stories that Germans are very strict or that is very difficult to work with them we are very happy to admit that it is NOT true! Each wednesday that we have our weekly call, we were very happy to talk with them and hear their feedback because it was really helpful for us, that’s why this is one of the things we will miss most! (Thank you guys :D)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Status updates, because they helped us keep track of what we achieved and to set goals for our team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being able to focus full-time on open-source development and community building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-in-all&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All in All…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a never-to-be-forgotten summer - one of those summers that leave a rich heritage of beautiful memories in their going. Is it the end? Definitely NO, our journey does not end here. We are both open source enthusiasts and the gained experience we had this summer has inspired us even more to continue contributing to coding part of open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks RGSoC for this amazing experience we had during this summer, we are happy to be one of the RGSoC alumni now and share our journey with other people!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 17:04:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/Rails-Girls-Summer-Of-Code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/Rails-Girls-Summer-Of-Code/</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>girlsintech</category>
        
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Led Zeppelin is the greatest band ever...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever done a &lt;strong&gt;Zeppathon&lt;/strong&gt;? When you sit your ass down and listen to all nine Led Zeppelin albums in a row. It takes about 7 hours to do. Every true fan must do it at least once in their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/ledzeppelin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Led Zeppelin&lt;/strong&gt; has gone down in history as one of the greastest bands of all time. I’m here to show you that they are, in fact, the greatest of them all (I believe).
Remembered as the biggest band of the 1970’s, Led Zeppelin gained iconic status through their electrifying live shows. Over time, their popularity hasn’t waned, and they are still one of the most popular bands today. Only reuniting a handful of times, they have remained true to their legacy and will be forever remembered as their classic line-up: &lt;strong&gt;Robert Plant, Jimmy Page, John Paul Jones, and John Bonham&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/ledzeppelin2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might say, “This sounds like you’re pandering to Led Zeppelin fans, I mean, not everybody likes them you know.  You can’t just say they were the best band to have ever existed and have it be true.”  If so, you’d be right.  Not everyone likes Led Zeppelin, and not everyone would say that they were the best band to have ever existed.  That’s not the point.  The point is: Led Zeppelin was a legend of a band—something that might not happen again, if not for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/ledzeppelin2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?” You ask.  Well, faithful reader, the answer lies in the artists.  Take Jimmy Page for example.  Page is no doubt an excellent guitarist, but what makes him so good?  Well for starters, at the time (the 70’s) he was at the epitome of guitar playing skill.  Give him anything, and he could play it.  Not only this, but he was also what rock-fanatics might call a “riff machine.”  This man would spit out iconic riff after riff, making every song incredibly catchy.  Take their 1971 hit “Black Dog” for instance.  “Black Dog” is entirely driven by Jimmy’s riff, repeating through breaks of Robert Plant’s wailing vocals.  Songs that were given the power of Page’s iconic riffs became rock staples.  Now that might be enough to call him one of the best, but he’s not done.  One of Led Zeppelin’s key factors is their solo potential.  Jimmy Page could solo, and he could solo hard.  Really hard.  The hardest.  From the iconic “Stairway to Heaven” to the short and sweet “Whole Lotta Love” solo, Jimmy demonstrated absolute dominance over the industry in practically every song.  His skill combined with his fellow band members’ proved to be one of the best in the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/robertplant.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of fellow band members, on to the glorious Robert Plant.  Plant, the singer, was the spitting image of “showman.”  He had the long blond hair, the extra-skinny skinny jeans, and the staple unbuttoned shirt purposely exposing his entire torso.  And he had the stance, too.  When singing, he would stand perpendicular to the crowd with his right hand raised to eye level, his finger lazily pointing upwards while he moved his hand around without much of a pattern.  He was so feminine that he was incredibly masculine. The man was a legend for several reasons.  Aside from the look, he had the voice.  He was characteristic for his screeching wails and charisma, and he commanded the stage with ease.  His voice gave a twisted, darker sound most of the time, but can easily be happy or bluesy.  Robert Plant’s voice is really what gives a Led Zeppelin song its flair, and without it the songs wouldn’t feel the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/jimmypage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Page and Plant were known as the flagships for the band, but don’t forget about the forgotten duo:  John Paul Jones and John Bonham.  Let’s begin with JPJ, because without him, most bassists wouldn’t have an idol. John Paul Jones will forever be the unsung hero of the group. His ability to creatively and skillfully craft new riffs on bass that could mimic the guitar riffs gave the songs an incredible drive, and he is also a multi-instrumentalist.  Not only did he play bass (which he was most famous for), he also plays the guitar, koto, lap steel guitars, mandolin, autoharp, violin, ukulele, sitar, cello, and recorder (as heard in “Stairway to Heaven”).  Not only does he play all of these instruments, he plays them well.  Well enough to use in whatever song the band needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/johnpauljones.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Bonham on the other hand was the glue that stuck the band together.  JPJ was the jack-of-all-trades, Page was the guitar wizard, and Plant was the showman, but Bonham had something that Led Zeppelin needed.  He was very dear to the band members, and kept them together and happy.  He was one of the best drummers to have ever existed, and was known for his speed, power, and groove. 
One only needs to listen to Moby Dick to recognise that John Bonham was an extraordinary drummer of seemingly limitless ability. His thunder can be heard on songs ranging from cock-rock classics such as Black Dog, to the beautiful ballads Over the Hills and Far Away and The Rain Song, to the folksy Bron-Y-Aur Stomp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/bonzo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, Led Zeppelin most definitely has what it takes to be one of the best bands in history.  The combination of skill, technique, genre, and a level of musical bravery to surpass the norms seen during its time lead the band to be incredibly memorable.  When listening to Led Zeppelin, almost all of their songs have become staples in American history.  Each member was at the peak of his trade and each added his own flavor to the music.  Led Zeppelin is so good in fact that I truly believe the world of music would be vastly different without them, more so than any other band in history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who can forget such classic lines as “Mean old levee, taught me to weep and moan”, or “I don’t know, but I been told, that big-legged women ain’t got no soul”.
Led Zeppelin’s lyrics have much of Lord Byron about them: grandiosity, majesty, and more than a handful of irreverence. The lyrics cover everything from love, to The Lord of the Rings, to sex in its sexiest form, to childhood friendship. Whether influenced by blues, folk or good old rock ‘n roll, Led Zeppelin’s lyrics encompass a wide range of experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guitar solo is a hallmark of rock ‘n roll and many artists are credited as being masters of the craft: from Jimi Hendrix to Slash. However, few solos carry as much emotion as Jimmy Page’s, whether we be listening to Since I’ve Been Loving You, Rock and Roll, or Stairway to Heaven. Page’s perfect mix of fast and slow passages, highs and lows, all set against Plant’s voice define the Led Zeppelin sound, and you’d be hard-pressed to find another artist who delivers the goods so succinctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/music/led.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Led Zeppelin will mostly forever be remembered as a rock band, whose classics such as Whole Lotta Love, Trampled Underfoot and Kashmir shook the foundations of the genre to its core. But there was another side to the Led Zeppelin coin, a side characterised by sensitivity, contemplation and beauty. Led Zeppelin authored some of the most beautiful ballads ever written, from the tribute to Plant’s deceased son All My Love, to the love song Thank You, to the hauntingly indescribable The Rain Song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my final reason, one everyone should hold dear, is the ability for Led Zeppelin to create songs of different, rather odd genres and still have them all turn out as a major commercial success.  Take the skill of each member and combine them into one song and you could make anything happen.  Their strong suit, the combination of hard rock and blues, was their defining factor—but they had much more.  “Stairway to Heaven,” some would say their magnum opus, almost lacks a genre.  It has a hard rock section at the end, but in the beginning (with the aforementioned medieval recorder section supplied by the wonderful John Paul Jones), it had an indiscernible, eerie sound.  “Over the Hills and Far Away” utilized an acoustic indie sound which led into some hard rock, and “Going to California” took that indie sound and ran with it for the whole song.  “What is and What Should Never Be” is almost indiscernible as well, yet does feel like hard rock at times.  Led Zeppelin had an artistic freedom in instrumentation, lyrics, and genre that none could rival, pushing them forth to be one of the most influential and creative (if not best) bands in history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-interesting-facts&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some interesting facts…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(source: https://ohfact.com)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1-Formation of Led Zeppelin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The band Led Zeppelin was formed by Jimmy Page in the year 1968 but at first it was named The New Yardbirds. Later they changed the name to Led Zeppelin. Jimmy Page wanted to name it Lead Zeppelin but he thought that the Americans might pronounce it ‘Leed’. So, he changed it to Led to leave no confusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-Jimmy Page and Black Magic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the success of the band Led Zeppelin, Jimmy Page was heavily interested in the black magic and dark arts. He even owned a book shop and publishing house based on occult. Due to this some people thought that the four symbols on the fourth album cover are satanic symbols. Well they are; but it’s not him, its “them”. Who is them ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3-Untitled Fourth album&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after the launch of three successful albums, Led Zeppelin, II, III; the press still called the Led Zeppelin band hype. So, when it was turn of the fourth album, the band decided not to print even a single word on the record sleeve. They even refused to print their names; instead they opted for four symbols on the cover and each symbol represented each member. Even though the symbol didn’t contain any letter yet it seems to spell ‘Zoso’ and people started referring the album by the name Zoso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4-Jimmy Page and the Double-neck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jimmy Page used Gibson’s double – necked guitar with ease and was one of the earliest adopter of this double – necked guitar. In a poll in 2012 his Gibson EDS – 1275 guitar was named the coolest guitar in rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5-New engineer for every album&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jimmy Page didn’t want anyone else to take credit for the sound of Zeppelin songs. So, he produced every record of the band himself and for each album he used to hire a new engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6-Only one TV appearance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Led Zeppelin had made only one TV appearance which was in June 1969 for a French TV. This is because after taping for the French TV appearance, they realized that the audio video quality of TV is quite low and no matter how well they performed they would be at the mercy of the studio engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7-The disbandment of Led Zeppelin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1980 John Bonham died after choking on his own vomit. This led to the disbandment of Led Zeppelin. Later on in an autopsy it was revealed that on the night of his death John Bonham had an equivalent of 40 shots of vodka in his body.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 16:04:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/Led-Zeppelin-The-Greatest-Band-Ever/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/Led-Zeppelin-The-Greatest-Band-Ever/</guid>
        
        <category>Music</category>
        
        <category>Rock</category>
        
        <category>Led Zeppelin</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who is Xheni?!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Xheni (en:Jenny) or xh3n1, is just a humanoid who has black hair and big eyes. She has always been the weird kid because she used to play football and video games while other girls played with dolls. Even though her dad wanted her to study medicine, she chose Business Informatics. Did you know that when she was a kid, she wanted to be a hacker ( That was her decision after watching the movie “hackers”). Currently, she is studying Msc in Information Security and one day she hopes to become a good ethical hacker ;). She mostly enjoys coding while she is drinking coffee and listening to good rock music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hacktoberfest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hactoberfest&quot; title=&quot;Stickers lover CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Xheni loves stickers CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xheni was a student of &lt;a href=&quot;https://teams.railsgirlssummerofcode.org/users/1703&quot;&gt;Rails Girls Summer of Code 2017&lt;/a&gt; working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt; project. She is a member of &lt;a href=&quot;https://openlabs.cc&quot;&gt;Open Labs Albania&lt;/a&gt;, a community which promotes free and open source technologies, open data, open technological standards, online privacy etc. She is a Linux lover and has tried many linux distributions. She loves animals (more than you :p). She likes books, movies and animes. She runs a meme page and loves Pepe. She speaks shqip, english and ein bisschen Deutsch. Try bribing her with chocolates. She believes in aliens, do you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/redshoes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;red shoes&quot; title=&quot; Oscal 2017 CC-BY-SA 4.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OSCAL 2017 CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 16:04:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/whoamI/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/whoamI/</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
